When you go on holiday, where do you like to stay?
度假时，你喜欢住在哪里？
Do you like the luxury of a five-star hotel, the convenience of a self-catering apartment or do you prefer the freedom of sleeping under canvas?
是偏爱五星级酒店的奢华、自助公寓的便利，还是更向往睡在帐篷里的无拘无束？
If you haven’t tried the latter, maybe you should join the increasing number of people who are enjoying the simple pleasures of camping.
如果你还没试过最后一种，或许你应该像越来越多的人一样，去体验露营带来的简单乐趣。
By grabbing your tent, and some additional accessories, it’s easy to head off to the countryside and enjoy a night or two under the stars.
带上帐篷和一些附加装备，很容易就可以前往郊外，在星空下度过一两晚。
Many campers are ditching the trappings of their modern, hectic life to do this, encouraged by experts who say a few peaceful nights in the middle of nowhere might be a good way to unwind and improve our sleep patterns and well-being.
许多露营爱好者都会抛开现代快节奏生活的繁琐羁绊，选择这样的休闲方式。专家也表示，在偏远宁静的地方度过几个平和的夜晚，或许是放松身心、改善睡眠规律与身心健康的好办法。
It is also, of course, a good low-budget holiday option.
当然，这也是一种低成本的度假选择。
For the adventurous, wild camping is the ultimate escape from reality.
对于热爱冒险的人来说，野外露营是逃离现实的终极方式。
Armed with just some food and a sleeping bag, you’re free from rules, away from other people, and able to enjoy the back-to-basics experience.
只带上些许食物和一个睡袋，你就能摆脱规则，远离人群，享受这种回归本真的体验。
One wild camper, Phoebe Smith, told the BBC: “The act of sleeping when everybody else has gone home – when you notice the wildlife and the stars – is one of the best things in life.”
野外露营爱好者菲比·史密斯在接受BBC采访时说：“当所有人都已归家，你却在户外入眠——留意着周围的野生动物和满天繁星，这是生活中最美好的事情之一。”
But for those who still want some home comforts, a campsite is a more suitable place to pitch your tent.
但对于那些仍想保留一些居家舒适的人来说，露营地会是更适合搭帐篷的地方。
Here you have facilities such as washrooms, a shop and maybe even a restaurant.
这里有洗手间、小卖部，甚至可能有餐厅之类的设施。
And for the most luxurious camping experience, you could try glamping.
而如果想体验最奢华的露营，你可以试试“精致露营”。
In the UK, camping – and caravanning – has always been popular.
在英国，露营以及房车旅行向来十分受欢迎。
One survey by Visit Britain found around 4.38 million people go camping in Britain every year.
英国旅游局的一项调查显示，每年约有438万人会在英国本土露营。
More recently, sales of camping gear have jumped as more people have opted for a staycation within the UK due to travel restrictions caused by the coronavirus pandemic.
近年来，受新冠疫情引发的旅行限制影响，更多人选择在英国境内度假，露营装备的销量也随之猛增。
One camping retailer, Halfords, reported a surge in demand for products such as stoves, cool boxes and camping chairs.
露营用品零售商哈福德公司报告称，炉具、冷藏箱和露营椅这类产品的需求激增。
With the addition of inflatable mattresses and pillows, powerful torches and lamps to light up your tent and a better selection of easy-to-cook food, you can almost guarantee a comfortable and enjoyable camping expedition.
有了充气床垫和枕头、能照亮帐篷的强光手电筒与灯具，再加上种类更丰富的易于烹饪的食材，你几乎能确保拥有一次舒适愉悦的露营之旅。
The only thing you can’t guarantee, in the UK at least, is good weather!
不过有一件事是无法保证的——至少在英国是这样——那就是晴朗的好天气！
So maybe it’s time to slum it and give camping a try.
所以，或许是时候放下精致，去体验一次露营了。